<refentry id="cvar.g_antiwarp">

<refmeta>
    <refentrytitle>g_antiwarp</refentrytitle>
    <manvolnum>cvar</manvolnum>
</refmeta>

<refnamediv>
    <refname>g_antiwarp</refname>
    <refpurpose>enable/set bitflags for antiwarp functionality</refpurpose>
</refnamediv>

<refsynopsisdiv>
    <cmdsynopsis>
        <command>g_antiwarp</command>
        <arg><replaceable>flags</replaceable></arg>
    </cmdsynopsis>

<table id="cvar.g_antiwarp.flags" frame="all">
<?dbfo table-width="30%"?>
<title>g_antiwarp Flags</title>
<tgroup cols="2" align="left" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
    <colspec colnum="1" colwidth="9*" align="center"/>
    <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="21*"/>
    <thead>
        <row>
            <entry>FLAG</entry>
            <entry>DESCRIPTION</entry>
        </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
        <row>
            <entry>1</entry>
            <entry>enable antiwarp functionality</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
            <entry>32</entry>
            <entry>log player's warping to their desktop</entry>
        </row>
    </tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsection>
<title>Default</title>
    <cmdsynopsis>
        <command>g_antiwarp</command>
        <arg choice="plain"><literal>1</literal></arg>
    </cmdsynopsis>
</refsection>

<refsection>
<title>Description</title>
<para>
    <command>g_antiwarp</command>
    enable/sets bitflags for antiwarp functionality.
</para>
<para>
    Warping occurs when the server recieves several new commands for a player in a very short period of time.
    This happens because packets from the player were lost or never sent.
    The player will appear to cross a great distance in a very short period of time,
    making them hard to hit and possibly allowing them to avoid landmine damage.
</para>
<para>
    The antiwarp system delays commands when they are recieved too quickly.
    Thus, when a player sends 700ms worth of commands in 50ms, the commands will be spread out over 700ms,
    causing the player to move smoothly to other players.
    This affects the player who sent the commands too quickly only by increasing their ping,
    and will not keep increasing ping endlessly - at maximum,
    the added ping is the highest ping the player is actually getting.
    If temporary network issues cause ping to increase beyond a sensible number,
    the player can stand still for a moment and their ping will normalize.
</para>
<para>
    The net effect is that players with unreliable or congested upstream will not benefit from their situation;
    rather they (in a sense) are penalized for it, while all the other players on the server are not.
</para>
<para>
    <caution>
        Flags enabling extra debug/logging can be extremely network-expensive and should
        not be used for normal gameplay.
    </caution>
</para>
<para>
    <note>
        The initial code implementation for antiwarp was contributed to &project:name;
        by &zinx:name;, June 2007.
    </note>
</para>
</refsection>

</refentry>
