<chapter id="client.features">
<title>Features</title>

<section id="client.features.adrenalineSharing">
<title>Adrenaline Sharing</title>
<para>
    You have the ability to share adrenaline with other players.
    If you switch to the alternate weapon of the adrenaline syringe (usually right click on the mouse),
    the syringe will point outwards and you can give a live teammate adrenaline.
    This is an excellent way to promote teamwork in tough situations.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_medics"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.alternateHUD">
<title>Alternate HUD</title>
<para>
    HUD is an acronym for
    <emphasis role="bold">Heads</emphasis> <emphasis role="bold">U</emphasis>p <emphasis role="bold">D</emphasis>isplay.
    This is the 2D layout of items are on your screen such as what weapon you’re holding, your compass,
    how much XP and health you have, etc. &project:name; has an alternative HUD available to use that
    takes up less screen space.
    This setting is available on the client using the in-game &project:name; preferences menu.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.autorate">
<title>Automatic Rate Adjustment</title>
<para>
    Automatic Rate Adjustment tunes the /rate setting to help deal with big servers
    running large maps with many players which will help to offer a better gaming experience.
    If the rate is ramped, it will only be ramped for the current map to avoid entering
    other servers with a rate which may get you kicked. In all cases, /rate ramping can only
    increase as high as the server's sv_maxrate setting.
</para>
<para>
    If &project:name; detects that you have the highest normal /rate setting of 25000 and
    Auto Rate is set to "auto step" under the Jaymod/Misc/Network menu, /rate will be raised
    in increments of 1000 when the server detects network congestion in the server -> client direction.
</para>
<para>
    If Auto Rate is set to "server max" then /rate will be increased in a similar fashion as "auto step"
    except that instead of increasing in increments of 1000 it will simply increase all at once and match sv_maxrate.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.classStealing">
<title>Class Stealing</title>
<para>
    Class stealing allows a player to steal a dead teammate’s class.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_covertops"/>.
</para>
<para>
    In order to steal a class, you stand over a dead teammate and hold your activate key,
    much as you would steal a uniform as a covert ops.
    When you finish stealing their class, you lose your class abilities and your current weapons.
    You will gain the weapon the dead player was using (on an empty clip, you must find ammo!)
    and all the abilities of their class.
    <tip>
        If the server administration has enabled it, when you are a disguised covert ops and steal a class,
        you keep the disguise even though you aren’t a covert ops anymore.
    </tip>
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.corpseDragging">
<title>Corpse Dragging</title>
<para>
    Corpse dragging allows a player to drag a dead body (awaiting &medic; revive) along the ground
    while depressing the activate-key.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_dragCorpse"/>.
    <tip>
        Use this to drag a teammate's body away from danger,
        or drag a dead enemy to a safe place for uniform stealing.
    </tip>
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.doubleJump">
<title>Double Jump</title>
<para>
    Double jump allows you to jump an extra time while in mid-air to gain more height.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_misc"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.goombaKilling">
<title>Goomba Killing</title>
<para>
    Alluding to the Mario Bros. days you can <emphasis>“goomba”</emphasis> kill
    people by landing on their heads. The farther you fall, the more damage you inflict.
    Also, if you land on someone’s head, it softens your fall.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_goomba"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.hitsounds">
<title>Hitsounds</title>
<para>
    This extremely popular feature makes a sound when you hit a player.
    This feature is enabled on the client using the in-game &project:name; preferences menu.
</para>
<para>
    The sound distinguishes between friendly/enemy hits,
    and depending on the server setting <xref linkend="cvar.g_hitmode"/>, the general body-part of player being hit.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.killingSprees">
<title>Killing Sprees</title>
<para>
    The game keeps track of player kills and presents Unreal-Tournament-like killing spree messages and sounds.
    This feature is enabled on the client using the in-game &project:name; preferences menu.
    This feature must also be enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_killingSpree"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.liveUniformStealing">
<title>Live Uniform Stealing</title>
<para>
    &covertops; can sneak behind someone and steal the pants right off of them!
    You must stay behind the player though.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_covertops"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.obituaries">
<title>Obituaries</title>
<para>
    By default, death messages (obituaries) will show up on the left-middle part of your screen.
    On larger servers where there are a lot of deaths, it may be desirable to relocate those
    messages to the chat area.
    This setting is available on the client using the in-game &project:name; preferences menu.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.panzerWar">
<title>Panzer War</title>
<para>
    Panzer war is a fun game-play mode made for destructionists.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_panzerWar"/>.
</para>
&feature.panzerwar;
</section>

<section id="client.features.playdead">
<title>Playdead</title>
<para>
    A popular &shrub:name; feature, playdead is enabled on the server
    using <xref linkend="cvar.g_playDead"/>.
</para>
&feature.playdead;
</section>

<section id="client.features.privateMessaging">
<title>Private Messaging</title>
<para>
    Private messaging allows one player to send a private message to another player or group of players
    on the same server.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_privateMessages"/>.
</para>
<para>
    To use this feature, simply go into the Misc section of the &project:name; menu, and bind a key to use it.
    You may also use private messages through the console or global chat window,
    but this method is deprecated and discouraged.
</para>
<para>
    You can find a player’s slot number by using the admin command <command>!listplayers</command>
    or the builtin command <command>/players</command> in your client console.
    This is the best way to make sure only one specific individual receives your message.
</para>
<para>
    You can also specify a partial name match. This is a shorthand way,
    but also allows for multiple people to receive the message.
    For example, sending a message to “dam” will send the message “hello!”
    to players “Adam” and “Damage”, since they both have “dam” in their name.
    Just be careful that you don’t make the partial name too generic or you might
    send your message to someone unintended!
</para>
<para>
    There is also the option to block Private Messages.
    With Admin System enabled, anyone who is equal to your level or lower will be unable
    to send you a Private Message if you are blocking them.
    Anyone above you, however, will still be able to do so.
    This allows server admins to use Private Messaging as a valuable tool.
    You can find this option also in the in-game &project:name; menu.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.poisonSyringes">
<title>Poison Syringes</title>
&feature.poisonSyringes;
</section>

<section id="client.features.sniperWar">
<title>Sniper War</title>
<para>
    Sniper war is a fun game-play mode made for sharpshooters.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_sniperWar"/>.
</para>
&feature.sniperwar;
</section>

<section id="client.features.poisonGasMines">
<title>Poison Gas Mines</title>
<para>
    Poison gas mines are a new weapon available to level-5 engineers
    behind the normal weaponbank for landmines.
    Level-5 engineers are able to use poison gas mines if enabled on the server using
    <xref linkend="cvar.g_sk5_eng"/>.
    Similar to S-mines, they bounce into the air, but release a deadly gas for a duration of time.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.poisonThrowingKnives">
<title>Poison Throwing Knives</title>
<para>
    Throwing knives will also poison whomever they hit.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_weapons"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.smines">
<title>S-mines</title>
<para>
    S-mines (A.K.A. Bouncing Betties) are a new weapon available to level-5 engineers
    behind the normal weaponbank for landmines.
    Level-5 engineers are able to use S-Mines if enabled on the server using
    <xref linkend="cvar.g_sk5_eng"/>.
</para>
<para>
    The German S-mine (Schrapnellmine in German), also known as the Bouncing Betty,
    is the best-known version of a class of mines known as bounding mines.
    These mines launch into the air at about waist height and explode, propelling shrapnel
    horizontally at lethal speeds. The S-mine was an anti-personnel landmine developed by
    Nazi Germany in the 1930s and used extensively by German forces during World War II.
    It was designed to be used in open areas to attack unshielded infantry.
    Until production ceased with the defeat of Germany in 1945, Germany produced over 1.93 million S-mines.
</para>
<para>
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.shoutcasting">
<title>Shoutcasting</title>
<para>
    Players with the server password specified by <xref linkend="cvar.g_shoutcastpassword"/>
    can use the shoutcasting feature. This is a beefed up version of spectating.
    Players will be able to see the names of players above their heads,
    see timers on dynamite, and see all landmines across the map.
    To login and logout, use the following client-console commands, respectively:
    <screen>/sclogin PASSWORD
/sclogout
</screen>
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.throwingKnives">
<title>Throwing Knives</title>
<para>
    Knives can be thrown. You will need to re-bind whatever key you are currently using
    for alternate weapon to use the new &project:name; command using the in-game &project:name; menu.
    It acts just like the alternate weapon function, with the addition of allowing very special control
    over throwing knives. To throw a knife, hold the alt-fire button and release.
    The longer you hold the knife (up to 1 second), the harder it is thrown.
    Knives react according to your momentum too – if you are strafing left when releasing,
    the knife will have a leftward vector as well.
    This feature is enabled on the server using <xref linkend="cvar.g_weapons"/>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.watermarks">
<title>Watermarks</title>
<para>
    Server admins have the option of displaying a small logo on every player’s screen
    using <xref linkend="cvar.g_watermark"/>.
    Usually this logo will fade after a specified period of time,
    but admins may decide to keep the logo for an extended or indefinite amount of time
    using <xref linkend="cvar.g_watermarkFadeAfter"/> and <xref linkend="cvar.g_watermarkFadeTime"/>.
    Clients can adjust the opacity or even completely disable this logo using the in-game
    &project:name; preferences menu.
</para>
</section>

<section id="client.features.m97">
<title>Winchester M1897</title>
<para>
    Winchester M1897 (A.K.A. M97) is a new weapon selection available for every class except &covertops;.
    It is a pump-action shotgun with an external hammer and tube magazine.
</para>
<para>
    The United States military used a short-barreled version known variously as the
    <emphasis>trench</emphasis> or <emphasis>riot</emphasis> shotgun.
    It was developed into a version issued to US troops during World War I.
    Unlike most modern pump-action shotguns, the Winchester Model 1897
    (versions of which were type classified as the Model 97 or M97 for short)
    fired each time the action closed with the trigger depressed (that is, it lacks a trigger disconnector).
    That and its 6-shot capacity made it extremely effective for close-combat,
    such that troops referred to it as a <emphasis>trench sweeper</emphasis>.
    It was used in limited numbers during World War II by the United States Army and Marine Corps.
</para>
<para>
    Reloading works different than most &et:name:abbr; weapons as you must load one shell at a time,
    and reloading can be interrupted by pressing (not necessarily holding) fire while reloading.
</para>
</section>

</chapter>
