<appendix id="credits">
<title>Thanks and Credits</title>

<simplesect id="credits.main">
<blockquote>
    <attribution>&jaybird:name;</attribution>
    <para>
        First and foremost, the most humble and sincere thanks go to everyone at
        <emphasis role="bold">&clanfu:name;</emphasis>
        for their help and participation in the development and testing of this mod.
        Without their generous support, this mod would not be in existence.
    </para>
    <para>
        My utmost, sincere thanks and appreciation go to
        <emphasis role="bold">&zinx:name;</emphasis>,
        <emphasis role="bold">Bani</emphasis>, and
        <emphasis role="bold">Forty</emphasis>
        for their contributions.
    </para>
    <para>
        Many, many thanks to
        <emphasis role="bold">&mxyzptlk:name;</emphasis>
        for his cross-platform build/release system, C++ conversion,
        generated document system and continued work on the mod.
    </para>
    <para>
        Thanks to
        <emphasis role="bold">Meyerinchains</emphasis>
        for his contribution of the M97 model and animations.
    </para>
    <para>
        Thanks to
        <emphasis role="bold">Jeremy “Dr. Evil” Swigart</emphasis>
        and the magic of the
        <emphasis role="bold">&omni:name;</emphasis>
        team for their continued help with the implementation and debugging
        support of &omni:name; in &project:name;.
    </para>
    <para>
        Thanks at
        <emphasis role="bold">Lazyphreak</emphasis>
        at the &project:name; forums for taking the time to get all the original Shrub flags.
    </para>
    <para>
        Thanks to
        <emphasis role="bold">&etpub:name;</emphasis>
        for the contribution to the &et:name:abbr; community in general.
        &project:name; incorporates modified bits of code from their project.
    </para>
    <para>
        There are several server admins that frequent the &project:name; forums assisting those that require it
        without hesitation or commission. They simply choose to contribute, and for that I thank all of you and
        hope you will continue what you do.
    </para>
    <para>
        Thanks to
        <emphasis role="bold">&sd:name:tm;</emphasis>
        for taking the time to develop and release an incredible free
        <emphasis role="bold">&idsoftware:name:tm;</emphasis>
        based game.
        They have made a good many fan because of their generosity and dedication to the gaming community.
        Thanks to the &sd:name;
        <emphasis role="bold">forums community</emphasis>
        for the help they provide to everyone wanting to mod for &et:name:abbr;.
    </para>
</blockquote>
</simplesect>
</appendix>
