<preface id="introduction">
<title>Introduction</title>

<para>
    &project:name; is an add-on modification to &et:name;.
    The idea for &project:name; came from the main features of &shrub:name;.
    &shrub:name; has long been out of date and unsupported, and with the instability
    issues that come with &shrub:name;, something had to be done to get a Shrub-like
    server-side mod that would provide most of the features, be stable, and be supported.
</para>
<para>
    This mod has long since far outgrown its original objectives and has moved on to implement more
    advanced features with client-side support. To keep things as simple as possible, only one pak
    file needs to be downloaded (on the fly) for clients connecting to a &project:name; server for
    the first time.
</para>
<para>
    With most of the &shrub:name; compatibility implementation complete,
    the focus has shifted to the requests of the community, many of which mirror features
    already implemented in &etpro:name;. This mod is becoming a rather well-rounded game play mod as a result.
    It is seeing more and more options that might be deemed competition-minded while maintaining its fun factor
    for pub environments.
</para>
<para>
    &project:name; is a closed source project originally forked from the &et:sdk;.
    In mid-2006 the entire code base was converted to compile cleanly in C++ .
    Some &et:sdk; and all major &project:name; subsystems have been refactored/implemented
    to take full advantage of C++ language features.
</para>

<section id="introduction.download">
<title>Where to download</title>
<para>
    &project:name; is available for download at its official home <ulink url="&project:website;"/>.
    You may find versions available elsewhere on the internet, but if at all possible download
    it from the official homepage, as it always has the most up-to-date version available.
</para>
</section>

<section id="introduction.further">
<title>Further information and suggestions</title>
<para>
    If there is anything that isn’t answered here, I urge you to visit the website at <ulink url="&project:website;"/>
    for updated information, as it’s more likely to have information not available at the time this
    document was published.
</para>
<para>
    Also, I’m always on the lookout for good ideas or suggestions, so, again, please visit the website
    and let me know what you think!
</para>
</section>

</preface>
